Hello everyone, a very warm welcome to all of you,
you are watching User Real, I am your
own personal advisor Amit Raj Sharma. The host of today's
video goes to Mr. Subhneet
Chaudhary. Mr. Chaudhary,
thank you very much for your comment. Thank you
very much for commenting on Aditya
Birla Sun Life Insurance Company Limited
's Short Savings Plan
in the comment section of the video. If you all also want to
understand the details of the Short Savings Plan
with examples, then check out the Life Insurance playlist on the channel.
For your convenience, we have
already given the link of Life Insurance in the description of the video,
which will save your time. On
this note, please like and share the video and
tell us in the comment section that you
want the next video on this topic because
we are late. Every video is for your
questions and according to you, so on this note,
subscribe to the channel if you have not
done it yet because it will be useful for you. Let us
start today's video and know the
information about Aditya Birla Sun Life Insurance
Company Limited's Purna Suraksha Kavach Plan.
This is a comprehensive term insurance
plan. Now let us understand this line in our own words.  It
means this is a little term
plan where we will take cover as per our income, our
financial planning and our needs
because in this plan
we get six different variants
and all the six variants are kept separate from each other.
Now we do
not want any confusion, so in today's video we will
understand the information of the first three variants only. With an example, the first
variant is life cover. Life cover means
that it is a term plan of the basic plan where
only your life cover will be there and along with this
you will get its cover in the inbuilt terminal.
What happens will be
explained later, but before that, let us know the details of the eligibility criteria of the level
cover option i.e. option number one.
Andreas's limit is from 18 years
to 65 years, that is, people from 18 years to 65
years can choose the option and
they can remain under the governor till the maximum age of 85 years
because the maximum
maturity limit is 85 years. Premium
payment term means you get four different options.
With the level cover option, the first one
is single pay, that is, you will pay one time premium.  The
second is your regular pay, that is,
you will pay the premium for as many years as you are eligible.
Then the third option is
limited pay. Now, in this limited pay option,
you
get the option of premium payment term from 5 years to 20 years. The
fourth option is that you will pay the
premium till the age of 60 years. Okay, yes, when it comes to the
policy term, the
minimum option for the policy term is
5 years and maximum up to 55 years. But if you have
taken the limited pay option, then in such a case,
you will add five years to the minimum policy term premium payment term. And
if you have taken the regular pay option to pay the
premium, then
you will have to take a minimum positive of 10 years. The minimum
limit for the short term has been kept at Rs 30 lakh.
Now, when it comes to option number two,
option number two is return of premium. As the
name itself suggests,
our life cover will remain through the policy and when the
policy is completed,
we will get back whatever premium we have paid.
Okay, what we do is the
return of premium.  Regarding eligibility
criteria, we will watch the video
on full screen. The option number for return of premium in this
plan is entry limit,
maturity advance limit and minimum short term
limit. However, if we
take the regular pay option, then the
minimum premium will be 10 years and the maximum
premium payment term will be 55 years. You
get only three options here. If you
take single pay or limited pay, if you take the
premium payment term option of 6 years, 8 years or 10 years, then the
minimum premium will have to be 20 years and the
maximum is 55 years.
Whatever you bring in future is fine,
maximum 55 years in interval. Now the third
option comes here, early return of
premium. Now early return of premium
means that if you take this option while taking the plan, then
you will get another option along with life cover.
Within this, in this option,
you will be able to take
back whatever premium you have paid at the time of your retirement and
after that your life cover will remain till the end of the policy term. So, it simply
means
that after retirement  In this you will
not have to pay premium and you will remain under cover. The
retirement which is ahead
means that it is maturity, it will be less than that
but if you add 5 years to the premium payment
and add your age to it, then
your retirement will be advanced. There are
two options for premium payment term,
single pay and limited pay. There is an
option of 6 years, 8 years and 10 years. When it comes to
policy term, you will get the option of policy term,
minimum 20 years and
maximum 55 years. Rest of the entry limit, minimum
semester limit is same as option number two,
exactly equal. Now let us take an example here so that
we
can understand things here. We are taking an example here,
option number three which is early
return of premium. Mr. A is
35 years old, he
took a positive term of 50 years, he paid premium for 10 years
and he is 60 years old, here
retirement is ahead and the annual premium which will come
here will be ₹1 lakh 55 thousand, so
he will pay the total premium in 10 years.
15510 So as soon as he turns 60,
he will get this amount of Rs 1550.
Okay, as soon as he retires, those
who turn 60 will get Rs 1550000
back. Now how much will be left in the balance policy
term? 25 years. Now
this under cover will remain here for 25 years and
no premium will have to be paid and
if he dies within these remaining 25 years,
his nominee will be
given a claim benefit of Rs 1 crore. Okay, now when it
comes to the underlying,
in the early return of premium option we get the
option of guaranteed surrender value.
Now suppose after completion of 20 years of the policy,
sir, you surrender the policy here, then in
such a case the guaranteed surrender
value factor comes to 62%. Now
you will multiply this 62% by Rs 1550000
because that is the total weight premium, so
around Rs 9616 or  They will get
such cylinder value and the policy will be closed.
Now talking about guaranteed cylinder value, if
you take the single premium option then
you can surrender the policy from the first year itself.
If you have taken the limited pay option then you will be
able to surrender this policy after paying the premium for at least 2 years and
this option of guaranteed surrender value is
return of premium i.e. option
number two and early return of premium i.e.
option number one. We get the
facility of surrender in the seventh of the second option but you cannot make it guaranteed
cylinder value. Okay,
you can avail its surrender benefit.
You get a revival period of 5 years in this
and you will get the chart of surrender value in
PDF on the Telegram channel. Now let me take an example of this option
which is return of premium. Let me take an example of
Mr. A whose age is 35 years,
basic of ₹1 crore and is taking 50 years
positive. We are taking 10 years only, he
wants to pay the premium i.e. 10
years premium payment term, so annual
He will pay a premium of Rs 84700 only and
in 10 years he will pay a premium of Rs 847
and if he dies during the positive term
then he can get Rs 1 crore here in nine months
and if there is
no death and he survives the entire positive term then
Mr. will get Rs 847000
back here and if he
surrenders the policy in the 20th year of the policy then he will get
back 62% of the total paid premium, in
this way guaranteed center value, yes
in return of premium also you get guaranteed
underlying value as I
told you, now with return of premium i.e.
option number two and early return of
premium i.e. option number three you
also get the benefit of the policy, suppose
Mr. i.e. after paying premium for 4 years and
after that you are not paying two premiums, then
we will calculate the reduction payoff factor
here, we will divide 4
by 10 because the premium payment
term was 10 years, we paid premium for 4 years, so 0.4 is
our RPU factor i.e.  If the reduce paid
factor comes out, then in such a situation, if he
dies, then if we multiply the reduce paid factor by Rs 1 crore, then there will be a
death claim of Rs 40 lakh, which his nominee will
get. If he does not die through the
positive term, that is, if he
survives for 50 years, then his total benefit of Rs 33800 has
moved to the positive term, in this we will
multiply the PD factor of 0.4, then
₹13532 I am sorry
5203520 will be returned to him on maturity, so what do
we know from this, that it is a
reduce paid, we multiply
all the benefit
factors that are there in the policy,
in case of the policy, there is a condition that the
premium should have been paid continuously for at least the first two years, only
after that the policy will be able to
give the benefits of the reduce paid up policy, otherwise not, okay,
now whatever benefits are mentioned in option number two and three,
if the policy is
converted into a reduce paid up policy, then in that
we will add the RPF factor i.e. reduce paid up.  We
use the A factor and multiply it,
and the benefit is calculated as
I just told you. Now, let's consider the
level cover option.
Mr. B is 35 years old, has a
positive term of 50 years, and a premium
payment of 10 years. If we consider the basic sum assured and are taking a premium of Rs 1 crore, then we will pay a
premium of Rs 59,400 annually. In this way, if
we multiply the Rs 59,400 premium paid by 10 years by 10, then
this amount will become Rs 594.
If he dies during the policy term,
his nominee will be
given Rs 1 crore. The policy will be discontinued,
and with the life cover option, we do
not get the benefit of a reduced policy. However, with the other
three options, we get
terminal illness cover.
Terminal illness means an illness
which has been diagnosed by more than one medical practitioner and
declared that the
death of the patient, i.e., the
death of the insured, can occur within the next 6 months.
Its limit is that the terminal cover is  The policy will
remain in the plan only till the age of 80 years
and its maximum cover can be up
to ₹2 crore. The rest of the
actual cover is that if you
take a base sum of ₹1 crore, then 50% of it will be terminal
cover. If you get a terminal illness
and get a claim for it, then after that if
death occurs, then in such a case, the amount of the sum assured,
which is
50% of your base sum assured, is
reduced from the sum assured. Okay, and if the policy is
converted into a reduced sum assured policy, even then the
terminal illness cover remains here.
Option number two is with option number three, in
which the sum assured factor is reduced.
Okay, so
if death occurs after the terminal age, what will be the life cover?
We will subtract the sum assured from the
cover which has been done. Now
we will understand the details of the next three options in the next part
so that we do not get confused because we have to
understand with examples. If you
want to say something or have any suggestion, please
say it in the comment section, we will take every
single comment of yours.  Pay attention to them and
also note them down because according to that we
bring videos for you. Thank
you very much for watching the video till the end.
Please understand one thing yourself and
explain it to others also to your family members that
insurance is a protection.
Protection is never taken incompletely and
after watching the video,
definitely take the PDF from the Telegram channel and read it so that everything can be
understood easily. Thank you so much.